Finding Aid for University of Michigan Calendars, 1898-2016
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
University of Michigan calendars 1898-2016 1900-1950
University of Michigan.
0624 Bimu H1b 2
Wall and engagement calendars produced and published by Ann Arbor, Mich. firms such as George Wahr, Sheehan and Co., and designer Almira F. Lovell. Calendars feature contemporary photographs and drawings of the University of Michigan campus, people, and environs.
2 linear feet in 3 boxes
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Th calendars collection has been assembled from a number of sources.
The collection is open for use without restriction.
The University of Michigan Calendars collection has been assembled form a variety of sources and donations.
The wall and engagement calendars were produced and published by Ann Arbor, Mich. firms such as George Wahr, Sheehan and Co., and designer Almira F. Lovell. The calendars feature contemporary and historical photographs and drawings of the University of Michigan campus, people, and environs. The calendars are divided into two series: Wall Calendars and Engagement Calendars (1945-1968). All calendars are arranged by date within the series.
Subjects:
University of Michigan--Pictorial works.; University of Michigan--Calendars.
Contributors:
George Wahr Publishing Company.; Sheehan & Co.; Lovell, Almira F.
Genre Terms:
Calendars.
- Wall Calendars
  The first series, Wall Calendars, comprises two genres of calendars: those featuring photographs, and those featuring non-photographic illustrations. All include images of University of Michigan buildings and administrators. Most of the photographic calendars were published in the first half of the 20th century by George Wahr, bookseller and publisher of Ann Arbor, Michigan. The earliest calendars were often designed and arranged by Almira F. Lovell of Ann Arbor, who also worked with Sheehan and Company, another local bookseller and publisher. Although each wall calendar features a limited number of images, they tend to be relatively large, high quality reproductions.
  - Photographic
    (published by George Wahr, except as noted)
    - 1898 (Box 1)
      (no publisher; copyright Almira F. Lovell)
    - 1901 (Box 1)
      (Sheehan and Company)
    - 1903 (Box 1)
    - 1904 (Box 1)
    - 1906 (Box 1)
    - 1906 (Box 1)
    - 1907 (Box 1)
    - 1907 (Box 1)
    - 1908 (Box 1)
    - 1908 (Box 1)
    - 1908 (Box 1)
      (no publisher)
    - 1910 (Box 1)
    - 1910 (Box 1)
    - 1911 (Box 1)
    - 1911 (Box 1)
    - 1912 (Box 1)
    - 1912, leather cover (Box 1)
      (E.A. Wright, Philadelphia)
    - 1913 (Box 1)
    - 1914 (Box 3)
    - 1916 (Box 3)
    - 1917, calendar portion cut off; only images (Box 1)
    - 1917, suede cover (Box 1)
      (Made by Chas. L. Willard Co. for Theodore H. Conklin)
    - 1918 (Box 1)
    - 1919 (Box 1)
    - 1921 (Box 1)
    - 1922 (Box 1)
    - 1923 (Box 1)
    - 1924 (Box 1)
    - 1927 (Box 1)
    - 1929 (Box 1)
    - 1930, leather cover (Box 1)
      (E. A. Wright, Philadelphia)
    - 1932 (Box 1)
    - 1933 (Box 1)
    - 1936 (Box 1)
    - 1938 (Box 1)
    - 1939 (Box 1)
    - 1940 (Box 1)
    - 1941 (Box 1)
    - 1942 (Box 1)
    - 1943 (Box 1)
    - 1946 (Box 1)
    - 1947 (Box 1)
    - 1949 (Box 1)
    - 1952 (Box 1)
    - 1953 (Box 1)
    - 1987 "Sesquicentennial Perspective" (Box 1)
      (College of Literature, Science and the Arts)
    - "Vintage Michigan" Calendars
      (Produced by University of Michigan Alumni Association)
      - 2004 "Vintage Michigan, Classic Scenes of the University of Michigan and Ann Arbor", outsize (Box 3)
      - 2005 "Vintage Michigan, Classic Scenes of the University of Michigan and Ann Arbor", outsize (Box 3)
      - 2005 "Vintage Michigan, Football game day program art", outsize (Box 3)
      - 2006 "Vintage Michigan, Football game day program art", outsize (Box 3)
      - 2007 "Vintage Michigan, Football game day program art", outsize (Box 3)
      - 2008 "Vintage Michigan, Football game day program art", outsize (Box 3)
      - 2009 "Vintage Michigan, Football game day program art", outsize (Box 3)
      - 2012 "Vintage Michigan, Football game day program art", outsize (Box 3)
      - 2013 "Vintage Michigan, Football game day program art", outsize (Box 3)
      - 2014 "Vintage Michigan, Football game day program art", outsize (Box 3)
      - 2016 "Vintage Michigan, Football game day program art", outsize (Box 3)
  - Illustrated
    - 1982 (engravings by Philip C. Thompson), outsize (Box 3)
    - 1988 (Box 1)
      (College of Literature, Science and Arts; illustrations by Bill Burgard of architectural sculptural details)
    - 1989 "Campus Sculptures" (Box 1)
      (College of Literature, Science and Arts; illustrations by Bill Burgard)
    - 1989 (Box 1)
      (drawings by Bill Shurtliff)
    - 1998 (Box 1)
- Engagement Calendars
  The second series, Engagement Calendars, comprises calendars published by the University of Michigan Alumni Council, and the Michigan Union and League. The photographs reproduced in these calendars are generally smaller and of poorer quality than those in the Wall Calendars, but they are valuable because they generally feature more images of students and daily life at the University of Michigan. The Union-League calendars also include schedules of events held at the two organizations.
  - University of Michigan Alumni Council
    - 1945 (Box 2)
    - 1946 (Box 2)
    - 1947 (Box 2)
    - 1951 (Box 2)
  - Union-League Calendar Notebook
    - 1964-1965 (Box 2)
    - 1965-1966 (Box 2)
    - 1966-1967 (Box 2)
    - 1967-1968 (Box 2)
Additional calendars featuring University of Michigan athletics, primarily football are located in the University of Michigan Athletic Department record group.